

#### CONTACT



1 (226) 980-9134 Phone Number gsing994@gmail.com Email



www.GurmanSingh.com Website

#### **AWARDS**

Next 5% Award – 2019
Released two industry-leading software features
Advanced Micro Devices

Executive Spotlight - 2018
Directed the largest company
software launch
Advanced Micro Devices

**Director Spotlight - 2017** Created outstanding major product deck

Advanced Micro Devices

## **EDUCATION**

**B.Sc (Hons) - 2016** The University of Western Ontario

**SKILLS** 

PROCESS MANAGEMENT

MRD/PRD DEVELOPMENT

MARKETING STRATEGY

LRP FORECASTING

ISV RELATIONSHIP MANAGEMENT

KPI PLANNING



# Gurman Singh

# **Product Manager**

#### **SUMMARY**

An accomplished product management professional with over five years of bringing products to market. Experienced in strategy and leading large software releases driving over 300 million downloads and 500 million total views. Highly organized, detail-oriented, and conscientious self-starter, able to strategize and prioritize effectively to accomplish multiple tasks with creativity, enthusiasm, and autonomy.

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE



# Advanced Micro Devices (AMD) – Product Manager

May 2018 - Present

- Investigated and roadmapped innovative technologies (direct-to-GPU storage access and machine learning) with platform optimizations (SW+HW) to create unique features or enhanced performance
- Managed performance optimizations for new products innovation (NPI) to drive 15% greater performance
- Defined MRDs and PRDs tailored to specialized hardware to create consumer-focused features (i.e. game enhancements and streaming/recording platforms)
- Roadmapped and prioritized major software launches to improve user satisfaction to over 90%
- Prioritized major roadmap items for 70+ Radeon Software UX/UI features
- Represented AMD to global partners (OEMs/AIBS), showcasing new products and features, fielding questions, providing technical support and collecting feedback on current and future developments

## Advanced Micro Devices (AMD) - Product Marketing Specialist

June 2016 - May 2018

- Led five product and software launches gathering over 200 million total views
- Worked with product management to translate technical documentation and industry jargon into impactful storytelling used by PR for press releases and investor relations, along with social media for message amplification
- Analyzed campaign postmortems to develop recommendations with action items for future releases targeted at creating and improving company-wide KPIs
- Created marketing content for sales enablement, marketing newsletters, and customer-centric web content
- Represented AMD to champion software releases on world-wide press tours, i.e webcasts, events, press interviews, presentations, etc



# The University of Western Ontario - Microsoft Account Specialist

January 2015 - May 2016

- Built long term partnerships with customers to identify and sell SaaS/laaS products
- Drove the adoption of platform services through various channel-driven activations
- Recognized as a regional product expert and supported customers on software value



## Intercept Group - Microsoft Marketing Lead

August 2013 – December 2014

- Managed a cross-functional team to educate staff and students on Office365 products
- Stimulated product sales by creating and launching promotions for SaaS products
- Led social media marketing campaigns on Facebook and Twitter to increase brand awareness and purchase intent
- Conducted market research during seminars to gain valuable behavior preferences to better serve customers
- · Ensured marketing programs aligned with the overall strategy and vision of Microsoft Canada